Wilson Bernardo Bravo Ceballos

I am an Electronics Engineer and Full Stack Developer with experience in data management and problem-solving in software implementation. I am passionate about improving my skills and adding value to every project.

Phone: (+57) 323 386 5878 Email: <u>bravoc.wilson@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/wilson-bravo/

GitHub: github.com/WilsonBravo

Portfolio: nextjs-wilson-blog.vercel.app/

SKILLS

- Communication
- Creativity
- Teamwork
- Flexibility

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java.
- Frontend: React, Next.js, Vite.js, HTML, CSS.
- Backend: Node.js, Nest.js, Express, Fastify, Django, Spring Boot.
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Tools and Technologies: Git, Docker.

LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native

• English: Intermediate

• Japanese: Basic

EXPERIENCE

Partners Telecom Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia - Intern

AUGUST 2023 - JANUARY 2024

 Technologies used: Django, REST API, Grafana, Zabbix, AppDynamics, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

- I acquired knowledge of platforms and tools focused on monitoring IT systems. I developed a web application and implemented an API for interaction with databases and external applications.
- I optimized the data structure to enhance visualization, which facilitated more effective monitoring and proactive failure prevention.

Gabriel Betancourt Mejía, Bogotá, Colombia - Intern

FEBRUARY 2022 - JUNE 2022

 I taught technology and high school computer science, promoting engineering and technology. I developed engaging and educational activities to teach programming, encouraging active participation through practical exercises and experiments.

EDUCATION

Binary Studio Academy - Full Stack Developer

JULY 2024 - SEPTEMBER 2024

Bogotá, Colombia

Akura LATAM Oracle Next Education G6 - Backend Developer

JANUARY 2024 - JULY 2024

Bogotá, Colombia

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana - Electronics Engineer

JULY 2018 - MARCH 2024

Bogotá, Colombia

IEM Técnico Industrial - Technical Industrial High School Graduate with a Specialization in Electricity

JANUARY 2011 - DECEMBER 2017

Pasto, Colombia

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Fundamentals

IBM - SEPTEMBER 2023

Focused on Data Analysis, Databases, Data Science, Clean Data.

Honor Mention

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana - MARCH 2024

For excellence in the thesis work.

Oracle Next Education

Alura, Oracle - JULY 2024

- Focused on Backend development, Java, Spring Boot.
- Focused on Frontend development, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Database Patterns

Códigofacilito - MAY 2024

 Focused on applying patterns to optimize the structure and performance of databases.

Professional Docker Course

Códigofacilito - MAY 2024

• Training in the use of Docker for creating, deploying, and managing applications in containers.

Software Architecture Fundamentals Course

Códigofacilito - MAY 2024

 Introduction to principles and patterns of software architecture for designing scalable and efficient systems.

Google AI Essentials

Coursera - AUGUST 2024

Fundamentals of artificial intelligence and practical use of generative
Al tools for integration into the workplace.